## **Kusal Thiwanka**

Software Engineer

## Personal details



Kusal Thiwanka



mhkusalthiwanka@gmail.com



+65 8385 5820



704/5, Kulasewana Road 10230 Kottawa



September 18, 1995



Male



Sri Lankan



Single



kusalthiwanka.com



linkedin.com/in/kusal-thiwanka

## Skills

JavaScript	••••
React	••••
Python	••••
Django	••••
HTML / CSS	•••••
PHP	•••••
Solidity	••••
MySQL / PostgreSQL	••••
MongoDB	••••
REST APIs	••••
Linux Environment	••••
Docker	••••
CI / CD	••••

## **Profile**

I am Software Engineer with more than three years of experience on developing scalable web applications and working across the full stack. Experience in analysis, designing, development, implementation and testing of various internet base applications. Expert in several of languages and platforms. I'm utilizing my knowledge to solve practical problems in the real world and getting opportunities to step beyond my comfort zone and extend my expertise while providing significant service to the community.

## Education

#### **B.Sc.** (Hons) Information Technology

Jan 2016 - Mar 2020

University of Colombo, Colombo

#### **GCE Advanced Level & Ordinary Level**

Jan 2005 - Dec 2014

Mahanama College, Colombo

Mathematical Stream

## Certification

# Blockchain Specialization Certification

Sep 2020

**University at Buffalo** 

Online Coursera Certification - Grade 98%

#### Programming for Everybody (Python) University of Michigan

Jun 2020

Online Coursera Certification - Grade 99%

## **Employment**

#### **Software Engineer**

Apr 2020 - Present

#### KILATECH Software Development Company, Colombo

Work in KILATECH software development company as Software Engineer which involved in various projects covered software engineering concepts, development, testing and best practices. These are the main project that I was developed

- Shopify Applications Development (countdown timer, currency convertor, shipping bar etc.)
- Video Content Protection Service
- Shopify Applications Integration Supports

#### **Trainee Software Engineer**

Apr 2019 - Dec 2019

FMI (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo

Worked in Facilities Management Integrated (Pvt) Ltd in the Enterprise Development as a assistant software engineer which involved in various projects covered software engineering concepts, development, testing and best practices.

These are the main project that I was developed

- Proposal Management System
- Mailroom Tracking System
- FMI Feedback Mobile App

Apache & NginX

GCP / AWS

Git and GitHub

Moodle

WordPress & Shopify

## Languages

English Sinhala

#### References

#### Dr. Hiran H E Jayaweera, Senior Lecturer

University of Colombo, Sri Lanka hiran@phys.cmb.ac.lk

#### Mr. G P N Boteju

University of Colombo School of Computing, Sri Lanka gpn@ucsc.cmb.ac.lk

#### Mr. Rukshan Perera

FMI (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka rukshan.perera@fmi.lk

## **Projects**

### **Learning Management System**

This is a cloud base Learning Management System that include high-level video protection services. Teachers can manage their classes monthly base or course base.

• Django • React • REST • PostgreSQL • GCP

#### Online Video Player (Partnership with KILATECH)

This video player provides high level content protection service to secure your precious video content from being downloaded.

• Java • Django • React • REST • MongoDB • GCP

## **Custom POS System for Jewelry Shop**

This point of sales system has stock management, customer tracking and jewelry certificate printing options. This system that can help Inupa Jewelry company to speed up and manage their day to day works very efficiently.

• Django • React • REST • PostgreSQL • GCP

## **Custom CRM System (Final Year Research Project)**

This system that can help FMI company day to day works. Proposal Management System is a web application designed with many features to help the proposal creation process. And Mailroom Tracking system also a web base system that can track all internal and external delivery process

• PHP • JavaScript • HTML/CSS/Bootstrap • jQuery • Apache • MySQL

#### **Garbage Management System - IOT**

This system provides innovative and eco-friendly waste management solutions. This System has IOT device and Tracking Mobile app. IOT device identify garbage level and send data to server. Data is collected and monitored on our Mobile App.

• AVR • Arduino • Android Studio • Firebase

# Research Project

# Analyze and Redevelop Custom System (Industrial Research Project)

Undergraduate Industrial Research Project, University of Colombo, Sri Lanka Analyze exciting two separate generic system's weaknesses and adaptability issues and redeveloped cloud base multi-access custom system to manage proposal creation process and parcel tracking process.